Gothenburg, Sweden +46709637400 junsheng.fu@zenuity.com

# Junsheng Fu

GitHub Patents Homepage

I am a researcher in the field of computer vision and sensor fusion, with 8 patents, 6 publications and 13 open source projects. I enjoy applying Computer Vision and Deep Learning techniques to solve the challenges in autonomous driving.

**Technical skills** 

Languages: C++, Matlab, Python Frameworks: OpenCV, TensorFlow, Keras, CUDA, Git

## **Experience**

Zenuity

# Senior Algorithm Engineer

Sweden | 1.2018-Present

 Working on algorithm research and development of robust localization and road estimation for autonomous vehicles.

Nokia Research Center

### **Computer Vision Researcher**

Finland | 3.2012-12.2015

- Designed and implemented a 3D Map Augmented Photo gallery application with HERE Map (video).
- Designed and implemented an Interactive Video Playback System with HERE Map (video).

Tampere University of Technology

## **Research Assistant**

Finland | 9.2010-12.2011

- Designed and implemented a real-time video denoising filter with C.
- Embedded a denoising filter into H.264/AVC codecs.

# **Projects**

Vehicle localization

Demo

• Implemented a real-time particle filter to estimate the position and orientation of a moving vehicle.

Sensor fusion-based tracking

Demo

• Designed and implemented Extended Kalman Filter and Unscented Kalman Filter for object tracking.

Vehicle detection

**Demo** 

• Created vehicle detection and tracking pipeline with two approaches, deep neural networks (YOLO+TensorFlow) and support vector machines (HOG+OpenCV).

Lane departure warning

Demo

Designed and implemented a lane-finding algorithm and a lane-departure-warning system.

Driving behavioral cloning

**Demo** 

Built and trained a CNN to autonomously steer a car in a game simulator, using TensorFlow and Keras.

Camera Pose Estimation

Demo

Given a map contains street-view image and lidar, estimate the 6 DoF camera pose of a query image.

Road Segmentation

Demo

A neural network is trained to label the pixels of a road in images by using Fully Convolutional Network.

Traffic Sign Recognition

**Demo** 

Built and trained a deep neural network to classify traffic signs, using TensorFlow.

Path Planning

Demo

• Implement a simple real-time path planner in C++ to navigate a car around a simulated highway scenario, including other traffic, given waypoint, and sensor fusion data.

Model Predictive controller

Demo

This project uses a Model Predictive Control (MPC) to drive a car in a game simulator.

#### Education

| Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Computer Vision, Ph.D.   | GPA: 4.83 / 5 | 2017 |
|--|---------------|------|
| Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Signal Processing, M.Sc. | GPA: 4.45 / 5 | 2012 |
| Hangzhou Dianzi University, China - Telecommunication, B.Eng.        | GPA: 85 / 100 | 2009 |
| Udacity - Self-Driving-Car Engineer Nanodegree                       |               | 2017 |

#### **Patents & Publications**

- J. Fu, S. Pertuz, J. Matas, and J.K. Kämäräinen: "Performance analysis of single-query 6-DoF camera pose estimation in self-driving setups." CVIU, 2019.
- EP3161802A1, A method and technical equipment for determining a pose of a device, published 2017 (link).
- US 20160248985, Device with an Adaptive Camera Array, published 2016 (link).
- WO 2016102768 A1, Monitoring, published 2016 (link)
- EP 3051410 A1, An apparatus and associated methods for provision of wireless power, published 2016 (link)
- US 20160191796, Methods And Apparatuses For Directional View In Panoramic Content, published 2016 (link)
- US 20150155009, Method And Apparatus For Media Capture Device Position Estimate- Assisted Splicing Of Media, published 2015 (link)
- US 20140300775, Method and Apparatus for Determining Camera Location Information and/or Camera Pose Information According to a Global Coordinate System, published 2016 (<u>link</u>)
- US 20150109508, Method And Apparatus For Generating A Media Capture Request Using Camera Pose Information, published 2015 (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, K. Roimela, Y. You, and V.-V. Mattila: "A 3d Map Augmented Photo Gallery Application on Mobile Device", IEEE ICIP 2014, France (link)
- J. Fu, J.-K. Kämäräinen, A. Buch, and N. Krüger: "Indoor Objects and Outdoor Urban Scenes Recognition by 3D Visual Primitives", ACCV workshop 2014, Singapore (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, Y. You, and K. Roimela: "Augmented and Interactive Video Playback Based on Global Camera Pose", the 21st ACM Multimedia, 2013, Spain (link).
- L. Fan, J. Fu, Y. You, K. Roimela, P. Piippo and V.-V. Mattila, "Deja Vu: A 3D map augmented photo gallery application on mobile devices", In IEEE ICCV 2013, Demo session, Australia.
- J. Fu, E. Belyaev and K. Egiazarian: "Rate-distortion Oriented Joint Video Pre-filtering and Compression", the 10th conference of FRUCT, 2011, Finland (link).

# **Honors and Activities**

| TUT Graduate School Scholarship   | 2016-2017 |
|---|-----------|
| Nokia Foundation Scholarship  | 2014      |
| Sisu Award, Nokia Research Multimedia Technology Lab                            | 2013      |
| Runner-up in IIDA Idea Innovation Competition                                   | 2011      |
| Outstanding Graduate Award  | 2009      |
| <ul> <li>Chairman of Tampere Chinese Student and Scholar Association</li> </ul> | 2014-2015 |
| Chairman of one Badminton Club in Tampere                                       | 2012      |